Inventory of the Hamid Shawkat collection, 1952-2001
Hoover Institution Archives
Hamid Shawkat collection
1952-2001
2002C11
Shawkat, H?ami¯d
38 manuscript boxes (15.2 linear feet linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
This collection is comprised of newsletters, newspapers, journals, pamphlets, booklets, reports, and other writings issued by the Confederation of Iranian Students National Union (CISNU) and other Iranian student groups in Europe and abroad. These materials relate to political conditions and civil liberties in Iran, focusing primarily on the campaign for the rights of political prisoners; political opposition to the Pahlavi monarchy; the spread of Marxist-Leninist thought in Iran and among Iranian students abroad; the aftermath of the coup d'état against Mohammed Mosaddeq.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2002.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Hamid Shawkat was born in Tehran, Iran in 1949. At the age of 20, Shawkat moved to the United States and became involved in the student activist movement, which was united in opposition to the Pahlavi monarchy and the actions of its secret police, the SAVAK. He returned to Iran in 1978, amidst the turbulence of the Iranian Revolution. Soon after his return, Shawkat helped create the National Democratic Front of Iran and worked as an editor for the group?s central publication, Azadi. In addition to the National Democratic Front, several other groups, including the Democratic Party of Iranian Kurdistan, National Republicans of Iran, and the Left United Council for Democracy and Independence, joined the struggle for democracy in Iran. Since his time as a student activist, Shawkat has written heavily on the topic of Marxist theory and the rise and fall of the Iranian student movement, as embodied by the Confederation of Iranian Students, National Union.
Source: Hamid Shokat (2010). http://www.shokat.com/english.html.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection is comprised of newsletters, newspapers, journals, pamphlets, booklets, reports, and other writings issued by the Confederation of Iranian Students National Union (CISNU) and other Iranian student groups in Europe and abroad. The materials relate to political conditions and civil liberties in Iran, focusing primarily on the campaign for the rights of political prisoners; political opposition to the Pahlavi monarchy; the spread of Marxist-Leninist thought in Iran and among Iranian students abroad; and the aftermath of the coup d'état against Mohammed Mosaddeq in 1953.
Hamid Shawkat (or Hamid Shokat, as his name appears in published works) collected materials issued by CISNU and dozens of other Iranian student groups in Europe and the United States. Although primarily comprised of circulated newsletters, bulletins, and memoranda, the CISNU issuances provide insight into how Iranian students abroad were able to communicate, organize and, consequentially, create a united ideological front for defending the political and human rights of Iranian citizens.
Largely operating out of West Germany, between the 1960s to late 1970s, CISNU and its many chapters played a role in the proliferation of propaganda and demonstrations denouncing Reza Shah Pahlavi and his secret police, the SAVAK, for their violent suppression of political activists. To illustrate this violence, a number of articles and news bulletins included in the collection discuss the murder of German student Benno Ohnesorg in a 1967 protest organized by CISNU.
Although CISNU lost much of its student membership in the early 1980s, other revolutionary and student groups, including the National Front of Iran, Tudeh Party, Association of Iranian Writers in Exile, and People's Fedaii Guerillas of Iran continued to operate abroad, spreading awareness of their respective political views throughout Europe, Iran, and the surrounding Middle East.
Aside from publishing serial newsletters and circulating memoranda, Iranian Marxist, Communist, and Socialist parties, such as the United Communist Fighters, Party of Labour of Iran, and the People's Mujaheddin, distributed Farsi translations of notable works by Lenin, Lunacharsky, and Guevara. In addition to these works, 8 complete publications of writer and activist Mostafa Sho'aiyan are included in the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 7 series: CISNU Administrative Materials, CISNU Issuances, German CISNU Administrative Materials and Issuances, Other Revolutionary Groups' Issuances, Printed Materials, Clippings, and Miscellany.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Kunfiderāsīyun-i Jahān-ī Muhāssilīn va Dānishjuyān-i (Ittihād-i Millī); Iran--Politics and government--1941-1979; Iran--Politics and government--1979-1997; Civil rights--Iran; Communism--Iran; Iranians--Europe; Iranian students
Collection Contents
- Confederation of Iranian Students, National Union (CISNU) Administrative Materials, 1961-1986 (Box 1-3)
  Includes reports and minutes from CISNU and the Federation of Iranian Students (FIS) congresses and seminars; brief financial reports; forms and questionnaires distributed to CISNU members; and revisions of CISNU constitutions.
  The series is arranged into the following subseries: General, CISNU Congress Reports, FIS Congress Reports, CISNU Seminar Reports, and Miscellaneous Reports. Because almost every seminar and congress was assigned a unique number, the second and third subseries are arranged chronologically by official meeting number and date.
  - General, papers, 1961-1976 (Folder 1)
    - Addresses and zip codes of different student groups, 1976 (Folder 1: 1)
    - Constitutions, 1961-1976 (Folder 1: 2-3)
      Contains constitutions and other governing documents from various CISNU chapters.
    - Forms and questionnaires, 1966-1969 (Folder 1: 4)
    - Financial reports, 1965-1970 (Folder 1: 5-6)
      Includes a folder with itemized records of CISNU expenses for the years 1965-1966
    - Organizational bulletins, 1967-1968 (Folder 1: 7)
    - Schedule of events for student festival, 28 January-6 August 1968 (Folder 1: 8)
  - CISNU Congress Reports, 1965-1977 (Box 1-2)
    - No number, Paris, 1966 (Folder 1: 9)
    - 3rd, undated (Folder 1: 10)
    - 5th, 25-31 December 1965 (Folder 1: 11)
    - 8th, Karlsruhe, 1966 (Folder 1: 12)
    - 9th, Karlsruhe, 1969 (Folder 1: 13)
    - 10th, Mainz, 26 December, 1969-5 January, 1970 (Folder 1: 14)
    - 12th, Frankfurt, 1971 (Folder 1: 15)
    - 14th, Frankfurt, 6-11 January 1973 (Folder 1: 16)
    - 15th, Frankfurt, 2-11 January 1974 (Folder 2: 1)
    - 16th, Frankfurt, undated (Folder 2: 2)
    - 17th, Frankfurt, 2-5 January 1976 and 24-28 April 1977 (Folder 2: 3)
    - 17th, Hamburg, 27-30 December 1976 (Folder 2: 4)
    - 18th, Frankfurt, 4-13 January 1977 (Folder 2: 5)
  - Federation of Iranian Students (FIS) Congress Reports, 1961-1970 (Box 2)
    - 2nd, 13 August 1961 (Folder 2: 6)
    - 3rd, Karlsruhe, undated (Folder 2: 7)
    - 4th, Rome, 13 April 1966 (Folder 2: 8)
    - 5th, 17 August 1964-19 August 1965 (Folder 2: 9)
    - 7th, Hamburg, November, 1965 (Folder 2: 10)
    - 8th, Karlsruhe, undated (Folder 2: 11)
    - 10th, Mainz, 1968 (Folder 2: 12)
    - 11th, Mainz, 15-20 August 1969 (Folder 2: 13)
    - 13th, Darmstadt, 1970 (Folder 2: 14)
  - CISNU Seminar Reports, 1966-1976 (Box 2-3)
    Reports from seminars held throughout Europe and involving different CISNU organizations.
    - 3rd, Viareggio, Italy, September 1966 (Folder 2: 15)
    - 4th, Graz, Austria, August-November, 1966 (Folder 2: 16)
    - 5th, Florence, April 1967 (Folder 2: 17)
    - 6th, Riccione, Italy, September 1967 (Folder 2: 18)
    - 8th, Graz, June 1968 (Folder 3: 1)
    - 9th, Rimini, Italy, September, 1968 (Folder 3: 2)
    - 10th, Italy, 1-7 September 1976 (Folder 3: 3)
    - 11th, Augsburg, Germany, 13-15 June 1969 (Folder 3: 4)
    - 13th, Italy, 1973 (Folder 3: 5)
    - 14th, Italy, August 1971 (Folder 3: 6)
    - 15th, Riva, 20-23 August 1972 (Folder 3: 7)
    - 18th, Fanu, Italy, 3 September-20 October 1974 (Folder 3: 8)
    - 18th, Frankfurt, 5 January 1977 (Folder 3: 9)
  - Miscellaneous reports from meetings and seminars, 1965-1986 (Box 3)
    - FIS seminar reports, 1969-1973 (Folder 3: 10-11)
    - Report from general conference of students, Frankfurt, 1978 (Folder 3: 12)
    - Report to 13th congress from Iranian students in U.S., Los Angeles, 26-28 August 1966 (Folder 3: 13)
    - The Results of the Seminar in Mainz, booklet, 1986 (Folder 3: 14)
      Topic of seminar is the relationship between the radical left and Khomeini's regime in Iran.
    - Report from Dr. Heldmann to Amnesty International, October 1970 (Folder 3: 15)
    - Reports from meetings on the topic of women in Iran, undated (Folder 3: 16)
    - FIS report from conference on earthquake in Iran, 1969 (Folder 3: 17)
    - Seminar report from 4th CISNU congress in Köln, 1965 (Folder 3: 18)
- CISNU Issuances, 1952-1987 (Box 3-13)
  Newsletters, bulletins, printed materials, and other writings distributed by CISNU and related groups are included in this series. The content of these issuances ranges from announcements about protests, upcoming meetings, denouncements of the Pahlavi monarchy, and informational bulletins regarding political events and movements around the world.
  The series is arranged by format into the following subseries: CISNU newsletters and bulletins, FIS newsletters and bulletins, Newsletters and bulletins from CISNU chapters, Poetry, Press releases, and Printed materials.
  - CISNU newsletters and bulletins, 1961-1987 (Box 3-4)
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - Undated (Folder 3: 19)
    - 1961-1965 (Folder 3: 20-21)
    - 1966 (Folder 3: 22)
    - 1967 (Folder 4: 1)
    - 1968 (Folder 4: 2-3)
    - 1969 (Folder 1: 4-5)
    - 1970-1973 (Folder 4: 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Folder 4: 7)
    - 1976-1977 (Folder 4: 8-10)
    - 1978-1987 (Folder 4: 11)
  - FIS Newsletters and Bulletins, 1961-1976 (Box 5)
    - 1961-1966 (Folder 5: 1)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 5: 2-3)
    - 1969-1970 (Folder 5: 4)
    - 1974-1976 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Newsletters and bulletins from CISNU Chapters, 1967-1982 (Box 5-6)
    Arranged in alphabetical order by name of organization.
    - Association des Universitaires Iraniens en Europe (AUI), 1980-1982 (Folder 5: 6)
    - Federation of Iranian Students in Italy, 1967-1969 (Folder 5: 7-8)
    - Iranian Students Association in the United States (ISAUS), 1963-1978 (Folder 5: 9-10)
    - Organization of Iranian Students in America, 1967 (Folder 5: 11)
    - Iranian Students at Köln University, 1967 (Folder 6: 1)
    - Organization of Iranian Students Filled with Logic, 1977-1978 (Folder 6: 2)
    - Organization of Iranian Students of Karlsruhe, 1975 (Folder 6: 3)
    - Organization of Iranian Students in Mainz, 1955-1970 (Folder 6: 4)
      Includes newsletters from the Iranian Student Union on the campus of Johannes Gutenberg University in Mainz
    - Organization of Iranian Students in Mainz, 1971-1978 (Folder 6: 5)
    - Union des Etudiants Iraniens en France (Union of Iranian Students in France) (UEIF), 1963-1978 (Folder 6: 6)
    - UEIF, Khabar va gozāresh, no. 6 and nos. 3-12, 14-15, 21-22, 27, and 30, serial newsletter, 1975-1977 (Folder 6: 7)
    - Union of Iranian Students in England, report, undated (Folder 6: 8)
    - Union of Iranian Students in Hamburg, 1967 (Folder 6: 9)
  - Poetry, 1956-1973 (Folder 6)
    - Books of poetry published by CISNU, 1972-1973 (Folder 6: 10)
    - Booklets of revolutionary poetry issued by CISNU chapters, 1956-1966 (Folder 6: 11)
    - Patriotic Ballades and Poems, pamphlet, December 1968 (Folder 6: 12)
    - Āvāz-hāyeh band, booklet, 1975 (Folder 6: 13)
    - Miscellaneous poetry, undated (Folder 6: 14)
  - Press releases, 1965-1968 (Box 6)
    - November 1965 (Folder 6: 15)
    - March-May 1967 (Folder 6: 16)
    - March-September 1968 (Folder 6: 17)
  - Printed materials, 1952-1979 (Box 7-12)
    Arranged in alphabetical order by title.
    - Afq-i roshan, Ahmad Shamelu, pamphlet, 1978 (Folder 7: 1)
    - Anjuman, nos. 1-3, and 5, newsletters, 1977-1978 (Folder 7: 2)
    - Avaleh bahmān,, monthly publication of the Confederation of Students in Turkey, nos. 1-2, journals, 1977 (Folder 7: 3)
    - Bulitan-i dafā'ī, bulletins and newspapers, 1976-1977 (Folder 7: 4)
      Folder includes 9 issues.
    - Bulitan-i ihti'sāb-ī ghazā-yi markazī-ye kunfidirāsīyun dar pārīs, no. 2, bulletin, December 1976 (Folder 7: 5)
      Covers the events of a hunger strike in Paris.
    - Bulitan-i khabarī, no. 1, journal, 1979 (Folder 7: 6)
    - Bulitan-i khabarī-ye federasīyun āllemān, nos. 4-5, journal and booklet, 1975 (Folder 7: 7)
    - Bulitan-i kunfidirāsīyun-i jahānī muhassalin va dānishjuyān-i īrānī, booklet, December 1971 (Folder 7: 8)
    - Bulitan-i kunfidirasīyun-i jahāni-ī muhassalīn va dānishjuyān-i īrānī, nos. 4-7, booklets, 1972-1973 (Folder 7: 9)
    - Dah dāstān va nivisht-hāyeh dīgar az Fereydoon Tonekabonī, book, 1971 (Folder 7: 10)
    - Dānishju, quarterly review of the ISAUS, pamphlets and journals, 1965-1976 (Folder 7: 11-12)
    - Hamgam, nos. 9-10, 1962 (Folder 7: 13)
      German issue filed in GERMAN CISNU ADMINISTRATIVE AND ISSUANCES series.
    - Junbish-i dānishju bar sar-i daw rāhī, article, November 1980 (Folder 7: 14)
    - Kunfidirāsīyun-i dānishjuyān-i īrānī, 1975 (Folder 7: 15)
    - Māh nāmeh, newsletters and journals, 1963-1965 (Folder 8: 1)
    - Mard, Mahmoud Dolat Abādi (UEIF), booklet, undated (Folder 8: 2)
    - Mobārez, newsletters, 1976-1977 (Folder 8: 3)
    - Masā'il īrān dar m'atbou'at-i jahān (Iran in the News of the World), booklets, May and August 1971 (Folder 8: 4)
    - Nāmeh-ye dānishjuyān-i īrānī, organ of Students at the University of Bonn, nos. 1, 6-10, journals, 1952 (Folder 8: 5)
    - Nāmeh-ye dānishjuyān-i īrānī, nos. 11-14, 17-18, journals, 1952-1953 (Folder 8: 6)
    - Nāmeh-ye dānishjuyān-i īrānī, nos. 19-23, journals, 1954 (Folder 8: 7)
    - Nāmeh pārsī, quarterly cultural review of CISNU (Folder 8-9:)
      - 1959 (Folder 8: 8-9)
      - 1963 (Folder 8: 10)
      - 1964 (Folder 8: 11)
      - October 1966-December 1967 (Folder 9: 1)
      - 1968-1969 (Folder 9: 2)
      - 1970-1971 (Folder 9: 3)
      - 1972 (Folder 9: 4)
      - 1973-1974 (Folder 9: 5)
      - 1976 (Folder 9: 6)
    - Nāmeh-ye sāzemān, organ of the Organization of Iranian Students in Munich, nos. 4-5,and 8, 1954 (Folder 10: 1)
    - Nāmeh-ye sāzmān-i dānishjuyān-i Köln, 1953-1954 (Folder 10: 2)
    - Navīd, organ of the National Organization of Iranian Women, journal, 1967 (Folder 10: 3)
    - Parah'ī az asnād-i Savak, book, December 1976 (Folder 10: 4)
    - Payām, publication of the Organization of Iranian Students in Mainz, nos. 1, 3, and 4, 1972-1973 (Folder 10: 5)
    - Payām, journals, 1973-1974 (Folder 10: 6)
    - Payām āzādi, no.2, newspaper, 1979 (Folder 10: 7)
    - Payām dānishju, organ of the National Front of University Students, journals, 1961-1965 (Folder 10: 8)
    - Payām dānishju, no. 6, journal, 1974 (Folder 10: 9)
    - Payām dānishju, no. 1, journal, 1976 (Folder 10: 10)
    - Payām dānishju, nos. 3-4, journals, 1977 (Folder 10: 11)
    - Payām dānishju, nos. 1, 4-5, 8-9, journals, 1978-1979 (Folder 10: 12)
    - Payām dānishjuyān, monthly publication for Iranian Students in Mainz, journal, undated (Folder 11: 1)
    - Paymān, publication for the Defense of Iranian Graduates, newsletters, 20 May 1965-10 February 1966 (Folder 11: 2)
    - Paymān, defense organ of CISNU (Folder 11:)
      - 1968-1970 (Folder 11: 3)
      - 1971-1972 (Folder 11: 4)
      - 1973-1974 (Folder 11: 5)
      - 1975 (Folder 11: 6)
      - 1976-1978 (Folder 11: 7)
    - Pazhvak, defense organ of CISNU, newsletters, October 1976-May 1977 (Folder 11: 8)
    - Payvand, publication of Iranian Students in Italy, booklets, June 1973 and October 1975 (Folder 11: 9)
    - Payvand, pubilcation of Iranian Students in Munich, nos. 2 and 4, journals, March 1960-January 1961 (Folder 11: 10)
    - Payvand, no.2, journal, 1962 (Folder 11: 11)
    - Pīk-i dānishju, no. 7, newsletter, April 1978 (Folder 11: 12)
    - Pooyā, organ of the Federation of Iranian Students in France, booklets, 1956 (Folder 11: 13)
    - Razmeh dānishju, publication of the Organization of Iranian Students in America, nos. 1-3, booklets, 1976-1978 (Folder 12: 1)
    - Sedā-yeh dānishju, newsletter, 1977 (Folder 12: 2)
    - Siyāsat nazamigāri-yi rezhīm- īrān, booklets, 1973 (Folder 12: 3)
    - Sehpehr, publication of the Organization of Iranian Students in Frankfurt, nos. 1-4, booklets, 1975-1977 (Folder 12: 4)
    - Setārkhān bāh-yehraghī, nos. 6-7, newspapers, 1977 (Folder 12: 5)
      In Azerbaijani
    - Shānzdahomeh āzar, official monthly bulletin of CISNU (Folder 12:)
      The name of this publication (the 16th of Azar) represents the day in 1953 when three Iranian students from Tehran University were killed by the SAVAK.
      - 1965-1966 (Folder 12: 6)
        3 issues
      - 1967 (Folder 12: 7)
      - 1968 (Folder 12: 8)
        5 issues
      - 1969 (Folder 12: 9)
      - 1970 (Folder 12: 10)
        9 issues
      - 1971 (Folder 12: 11-12)
        15 issues
      - 1972 (Folder 12: 13)
        22 issues
      - 1973 (Folder 12: 14)
        19 issues
      - 1974 (Folder 12: 15)
        6 issues
      - 1975 (Folder 12: 16)
      - 1976 (Folder 12: 17)
      - 1977 (Folder 12: 18)
        21 issues
      - 1978 (Folder 12: 19)
      - 1979 (Folder 12: 20)
    - Zan, organ of the Organization of Iranian Women from Around the World, journal, January 1965 (Folder 12: 21)
  - Miscellaneous issuances, papers and reports, 1962-1979 (Box 13)
    - Articles, 1961 (Folder 13: 1)
    - Articles and reports, 1962-1976 (Folder 13: 2-3)
    - Collection of issuances from Iranian student groups, article, 1978 (Folder 13: 4)
    - General reports from Iranian students in Europe, 1962-1967 (Folder 13: 5)
    - Iran va komak-hāyeh khārijī, report, undated (Folder 13: 6)
    - Leaflets and pamphlets, 1971-1977 (Folder 13: 7)
    - Notes and writings, 1966-1969 (Folder 13: 8)
    - Notes and writings, 1970-1976 (Folder 13: 9)
    - Pamphlets issued by Iranian student groups in West Germany, 1971-1977 (Folder 13: 10)
    - Papers, 1963-1978 (Folder 13: 11-12)
    - Papers on political prisoners, 1978 (Folder 13: 13)
    - Publications, 1973-1975 (Folder 13: 14)
- German CISNU Administrative Materials and Issuances, 1963-1981 (Box 14)
  This series includes correspondences, newsletters, and printed materials similar to the CISNU Administrative Materials and CISNU Issuances series, however in German. The correspondence includes information about student alliances on the campus of Johannes Gutenberg University, as well as information regarding the assault and arrest of Mansour Bajatzadeh at a protest rally.
  - General, brochures and papers, circa 1967 (Box 14)
    - Brochure with map of Heidelberg, undated (Folder 14: 1)
    - Miscellany, undated (Folder 14: 2)
    - Schedule of events for Evangelical students of Mainz, January 1967 (Folder 14: 3)
    - Student petitions denouncing threats of expulsion for CISNU members, undated (Folder 14: 4)
      Includes 13 pages of signatures.
  - Correspondence, 1963-1975 (Box 14)
    - Allgemeiner Studenten-Ausschuss (ASTA), 4 June, 1964-16 November 1967 (Folder 14: 5)
    - Baghai, Fariborz, 13 February-20 December 1965 (Folder 14: 6)
      Letters written on behalf of the Iranian Student Union.
    - Bajatzadeh, Dr. Mansour, 20 December 1966-27 November 1967 (Folder 14: 7)
      Includes letters regarding Dr. Bajatzadeh?s violent arrest at a student protest in Mainz.
    - Heldmann, Dr. Hans H., 20 June-13 August 1967 (Folder 14: 8)
    - Iranischen Studentenverein der Johannes Gutenberg-Universitat Mainz, 1963-1969 (Folder 14: 9)
    - Miscellaneous corresondence, 26 April 1963-20 December 1975 (Folder 14: 10)
    - Rohrbach, Dr. Hans, administrator at Johannes Gutenberg University, 29 December 1966-6 January 1967 (Folder 14: 11)
  - Circulated newsletters and memoranda, 1962-1981 (Box 14)
    - 1962-1965 (Folder 14: 12)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 14: 13)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 14: 14)
    - 1970-1973 (Folder 14: 15)
    - 1975-1977 (Folder 14: 16)
    - 1978 (Folder 14: 17)
    - 1981 (Folder 14: 18)
    - Undated (Folder 14: 19)
    - Flyers, circa 1968 (Folder 14: 20)
  - Printed materials, 1962-1982 (Box 14)
    - ASTA Info, newspaper, 1977 (Folder 14: 21)
    - Bericht, newsletter, February 1969 (Folder 14: 22)
    - Dokumentation, pamphlet, March 1972 (Folder 14: 23)
    - Gegendruck, newsletter, October 1978 (Folder 14: 24)
    - Hamgam, no. 9, journal, June/July 1962 (Folder 14: 25)
    - Iran Info, no. 3, newsletter, March 1982 (Folder 14: 26)
    - Iran Report, booklet, April 1977 (Folder 14: 27)
    - Kurier, no.163, pamphlet, 14 June, 1976 (Folder 14: 28)
      Includes photocopies of clippings.
    - Persische Renaissance in Iran, Dr. Christophe von Imhoffe, booklet, 1966 (Folder 14: 29)
- Other Revolutionary Groups' Issuances, 1961-2001 (Box 15-28)
  Newsletters, bulletins, newspapers, journals, pamphlets, books, and other writings distributed by Iranian opposition and revolutionary groups. The one poster in this collection appears in this series and was distributed by the Marxist Mujahidin group, (Peykar).
  The subseries are arranged in alphabetical order by name of revolutionary group or organization.
  - Anjumān jahānī khānevādeh-hāyeh shahdā va zendāniān-i sīyāsī īrānī (World Association of Families of Iranian Political Prisoners and Martyrs), newsletters, 1976 (Folder 15)
    - Newsletters, 1976 (Folder 15: 1)
  - Etehād-i anjemān-hāyeh islāmī dāneshjuyān dar urupā, 1976-1989 (Box 15)
    - Newsletters, 1978-1989 (Folder 15: 2-3)
    - Reports and summaries, 1976-1978 (Folder 15: 4)
    - Maktab-i mobārez, no. 21, book, 1976 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Etehād-i mobārzān-i kumunist (United Communist Fighters), journals, pamphlets, and newsletters, 1976-1983 (Folder 15)
    - Kārgar kumunīst, nos. 1-9, journals, 1983 (Folder 15: 6)
    - Bi-su-yi susīālīsm, political organ, journals, 1980-1983 (Folder 15: 7-8)
    - Booklets, 1979-1980 (Folder 16: 1)
    - Events and planning pamphlets for first congress meeting, pamphlets, 1982 (Folder 16: 2)
    - Die Frauenfrage ist eine Arbeiterfrage, pamphlet, 9 March 1983 (Folder 16: 3)
    - Newsletters, 1979 (Folder 16: 4)
  - Etehād-i kumunīst-hā-yi īrān (United Communists of Iran), 1976-1979 (Box 16)
    - Haqīqat, newsletters, 1977 (Folder 16: 5)
    - Yād dāshte-hāyeh bar "Cheh bāyad kard?": nivishteh-yi yak moh'āfel mārksīst-lenīnīst, booklet, 1977 (Folder 15: 6)
    - Kumunīst, booklet, 1976 (Folder 16: 7)
    - Andīsheh-ye māu tseh dun va sīyāsat khārejī chīn, book, 1977 (Folder 16: 8)
    - Dar bāreh-ye āwzāh kānunī va vazā'īf-ī mā, book, undated (Folder 16: 9)
    - Report on the United Communists of Iran, 1979 (Folder 16: 10)